CURRICULUM VITAE

Nishant Kaushik Mobile: 7338427422

Email: nishantkaushik869@gmail.com

Location: Bangalore







Professional Summary

Full stack developer with 5+ years of experience in application development using different technology stacks. Involved in the application development stage starting from requirement analysis to feature release following Agile best practices.

Technology stacks mostly involved in are Nodejs, Angular 14, Typescript, Oracle Database 19c, Oracle Apex, Nest JS, Jest framework and Java (1.8).

Experience with different type of application architecture and third-party integrations. Extensively used functional and object-oriented style of programming following the best practices and pattern.

Core Competency

Frontend – Angular, Oracle APEX

Database technologies – Oracle database 19c, Mongo, SQL/PL SQL, Oracle No-SQL (SODA)

Backend – NodeJS, Nest JS, Core Java (1.8)

Event processing and message queue – Kafka

DevOps – Docker, GitHub

Testing – Jest

Professional Experience

1. Member of technical staff – II (MTS-II)

Electriphi – FordPro, Bangalore

January 2023 - Till Now

Roles and Responsibilities: -

- Working as a full stack JavaScript developer with toolkit as Nest JS, Node and Angular 14.
- Work closely with product owner, identify new requirements, analyze, break those into sub-tasks.
- Develop requirements into feature following best coding and agile practice. Write meaningful test cases to perform both e2e and unit test.

Acknowledgements: -

 Received a shout out for being a quick learner and getting involved in major initiatives.

2. Staff Solution Engineer

Oracle Corporation, Bangalore

April 2020 - January 2023

Roles and Responsibilities: -

- Working as staff solution engineer.
- Full stack developer and Consultant for GoldenGate for Big data, GoldenGate Stream analytics.
- Building application using Oracle application express.

Acknowledgements/Awards: -

- Received recognition and award for creating POC for Oracle's converged DB.
- Winner of Oracle's global hackathon (MadHacks) for consecutive years 2020 and 2021 and runner up in year 2022.
- Received recognition and award for creating Oracle APEX application to manage Joint execution documents.

3. Software Engineer

Quinnox Consultancy Services, Mumbai

March 2018 – April 2020

Roles and Responsibilities: -

- Direct client communication to understand new requirements.
- Working on estimates and creating JIRA backlog along with feasibility study.
- Working on JAVA application enhancements and development and performing initial round of Unit testing.
- Handing production issues.

Acknowledgements/Awards: -

- Received star performer award.
- Awarded for outstanding contribution in creating platform for collaboration and idea sharing (TORQ).

4. Software Trainee

ABIBA Systems, Bangalore

February 2017 – August 2017

Job description - 6 Month Paid Internship

Roles and Responsibilities: -

 Worked on migrating companies existing product to new and advance technology.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering from Acharya Institute of Technology, Bangalore, affiliated to Visvesvaraya Technological University (**VTU**).

Academic	University/Board	Percentage	Year of passing
B.E	VTU	67.99	2017
H.S.C	C.B.S.E	65	2013
S.S.C	C.B.S.E	82	2011

Personal Details

D.O.B: 16th March 1996
Marital Status: Married

• Address: B2 320, Saritha Splendor LSR, Seetharampalya Hoodi, Bangalore - 560048

Self-Accomplishment

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct and very much sincere as far my knowledge.

Place: Bangalore

Date: Nishant Kaushik